# **Maddie Wright**

UX and product designer

# Profile

UX designer passionate about developing highly performant digital products while bridging the gap between users, dev team, and key stakeholders in environments ranging from start-up to global enterprise. My experience also includes front-end development, web design, UX research, and product ownership.

# Employment History

**UX design consultant (Design system & B2B) at Micron Technology, Inc.**July 2023 — Present, remote

Global leader in innovative memory and storage solutions, providing DRAM, NAND, NOR, memory cards and SSDs.

- Partnered with web and creative teams to build and formally implement a global design system and accompanying UI component library in AEM.
- Wrote UX and accessibility guidelines as part of the new design system and integrated it into AEM for content author and designer access.
- Currently designing all phases of UX mock-ups for web implementation on projects including Micron University and Generative AI.
- Conducted UX research and analysis to explore and improve upon product designs and to stay abreast of best practices and industry changes.
- Figma, Adobe XD, AEM, Adobe analytics, Jira, Workfront, Adobe CS, Agile

# Digital experience lead (D2C & E-commerce) at Micron Commercial Products Group

 ${\sf March~2021-February~2023,~Boise,~ID}$ 

- Worked closely with Digital Marketing director to build a team of dedicated UX designers and front-end developers. I also helped onboard and served as mentor and coach for new team-members.
- As part of a company-wide initiative to strengthen E-commerce and brand presence on crucial.com, I led the UX strategy – working closely with SEO, product, and brand managers to re-structure the site navigation and shopping experience. The improvements resulted in 30% increase of task completion and notably reduced bounce rates on multiple pages.
- UX lead for tools optimization initiative that resulted in an overhaul of the branded product finder tools.
- Figma, Miro, UserTesting.com, AEM, Adobe Analytics, Adobe Test, Adobe Photoshop, Jira, Agile

# **UX specialist at Micron Commercial Products Group**

March 2019 — February 2021, Boise, ID

Micron's commercial brand, Crucial offers a wide range of memory and storage products worldwide.

- Created wireframes and high-fidelity mock-ups of all re-designed crucial.com pages as the sole UI/UX designer, which improved brand presence and E-commerce presence.
- Conducted rapid user research using various research tools, specifically
  Usertesting.com and Baymard Institute. Utilized Usertesting.com to
  identify user pain points by conducting interviews and by analyzing user
  session replays along with the click, hover, and engagement rates across

#### **Details**

Boise (willing to relocate), United States, 208-917-0543 maddi.chapman@gmail.com

# Links

LinkedIn profile
Portfolio website

#### Skills

Figma

Adobe XD

User Research

Adobe Analytics

UI/UX Wireframe Creation

Design systems

Requirements Gathering

Product Life Cycle

**Adobe Target** 

usertesting.com

HTML & CSS

#### **Hobbies**

Painting, illustrating, home gardening, travel, pets, museums, design, biking and hiking

- entire pages. Presentation of the results effectively resulted in crossfunctional buy-in to page optimization initiative.
- Performed internal website audit to identify ways to optimize the system scanner, cart/checkout, and solutions pages and followed through with ideation and cross-functional user journey workshops.
- Ensured designs were accessible for all users and ready for multiple language support.
- Close collaboration with local and offshore development teams to scope UX requirements and provide ongoing support and feedback.
- UXPin, XD, Usertesting.com, LucidCharts, Confluence, Jira, Agile, AEM

# Web designer at Blossom, Boise, ID

May 2017 — May 2019

Digital banking solutions for credit unions to change the way people experience money.

- Responsible for creating and presenting Credit union website wireframes based on client requests.
- Responsible for front-end build of approved designs using Bootstrap, CSS, and occasionally JS – led to 25+ successful website launches with positive client reviews on the customer experience.
- Frequent collaboration with CU clients to gather business requirements for new websites and website updates, including kick-off, progress checkins, wireframe presentation, and pos-launch reviews.
- Led an web-accessibility improvement initiative for all client websites, improving UI, flow, and code to better suit a broader range of customers.
- Helped prepare campaign graphics using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Adobe CS, JS

#### Intern, Website and product design at Stemfinity, Inc., Boise, ID

December 2014 — December 2016

# Clinical supervisor at Lilypad, LLC, Nampa, ID

January 2014 — May 2017

# Education

# Bachelor of Applied Science in Web Development,

Lewis-Clark State College, Lewiston, ID

#### Bachelor of Arts in Graphic Design,

University of Idaho, Moscow, ID

# Courses

# **UX certified, Nielson Norman Group**

April 2022 — April 2022, Washington DC

# "Improve your UX design skills" learning path, LinkedIn Learning

March 2023 — April 2023, online

### **Certified Scrum Product Owner, Scrum Alliance**

October 2021 — October 2021, online